call:(+91)-7760-109-322

Summary

Software engineer with about 4 years of pure product development experience on Java EE and web UI technologies. Always curious to know about latest technologies and methodologies in programming world.

Key Qualities & Experiences

- Expertise in developing User Interface, Business Logic, SQL
- Developing user-friendly and efficient Java based products
- Development based on agile and prototyping development model
- Development of RESTful web services
- Development using object oriented javascript and javascript frameworks
- Professional Image to HTML (PSDXHTML) conversion using the latest HTML5, CSS3 and jQuery technology

Software Skills

Core Skills :	Java/JEE(4), HTML5(3), CSS3(3), JavaScript(3), SQL(2.5), Oracle(2)		
	AJAX(3), JSON(3), jQuery(2), Spring(2), Jersey(2), HttpClient(2), Web Services(2), Apache Solr(2), JBoss(1), Tomcat(1), NoSQL(1), OpenShift(1)		
Tools:	Eclipse, Maven, Jenkins, YourKit Java Profiler, SoapUI		

^{*} Numbers in brackets show self rating for the particular skill out of 5

Employment

Thomson Reuters India, Bangalore March,2014 - Present Software Engineer

For the Life Sciences Product Cortellis

Developer for GUI modules of Cortellis product which mainly involves working with Spring, JSP, OO-Javascript and Web Services in an Agile work environment

- Worked with Cross-Functional Team at multiple locations in agile
- Product is built upon SOA with team divided into GUI, Middleware and Data Architecture
- Worked on GUI layer which involves consuming SOAP/REST webservices as well as designing web
 UI
- Worked on fixing bugs related to GUI layer which consists of a platform made up of Spring, JEE and Javascript with Continuous Integration using Jenkins
- Worked on a PoC project for next generation video transcription based product which earned industry wide acclaim for very quick development
- Experience in working with Apache Solr Search Engine and integration with Database
- Video Transcription based Product was designed and developed from scratch
- Had good beginner working experience with Spring Framework
- Investigated high priority Production Issues
- Optimizing the frontend performance using javascript/java profilers
- Completed Silver as well as Bronze application security internal certifications

Experienced in Java/JEE/Javascript

Spiramid LLC, USA (Oracle Gold Partner), Bangalore February, 2011 - February, 2014 Software Consultant

For SHE-MIS Environment, Health and Safety product through Indian subsidiary -

SH&E Systems Private Limited, Koramangala

SHE-MIS was one of the first Enterprise application developed by Oracle in the 90's later adopted by Spiramid

• Java/J2EE/Oracle Experience

- O Developed different features, modules and reports as per client requirements in SHE-MIS using latest technologies
- O Designed and Developed Automated Email Queue System
- O Designed and Developed Encrypted Link Based Authorization Web Service
- O Designed and Developed Email based Questionnaire with linked login
- O Performance Improvements for Reports that were over dependent on database query
- O Developed Web Service API to upload application specific files using HttpClient library
- O Developed Graphical Reports based on query results using third party library ChartDirector

• JavaScript/GUI Experience

- O Given the duty to work on UI of the product so as to adapt it to HTML5 and CSS3
- O Developed JSON based automatic input list of values that help save bandwidth using pure javascript
- O Conversion of legacy javascripts as well as user interface to modern technologies
- O Applied Responsive Web Design techniques so that the UI adapts to modern tablet devices
- O Development using Grid based layouts such as Foundation framework
- O Developed front-end prototype for the Next Generation SHE-MIS application using various improvements in javascript and HTML/CSS
- O Developed Drag & Drop based tables for better User Experience using HTML5 and Javascript

Professional Qualifications

Foradian Technologies, Mangalore June,2010 - September,2010 On Job Trainee (Web Technologies)

- Had good exposure in design aspects of UI development
- Had good learning experience in HTML and CSS Image to XHTML conversion
- Presented seminar on HTML5 and CSS3 latest developments
- Had intermediate experience in jQuery technology and plugins
- Had experience in creating vector images using Illustrator, Inkscape etc.
- Had experience in using image editors Photoshop, GIMP etc.

Academic Qualifications

Qualification	Percentage	Institution	Course Year	University
B.Tech in CSE	65.19%	College of Engineering, Trikaripur	2006-2010	CUSAT
Pre-University	89.00%	DHSS, Kanhangad	2004-2006	Kerala HSE Board
SSLC	89.33%	RHS, Nileshwar	2004	Kerala State Board

call:(+91)-7760-109-322

Personal Information

Name: BABU VIGNESH

Father's Name: SUBRAYA PAI DINESH

Date Of Birth: 26 - DEC - 1988

Address: 2F#44, 2ND MAIN 'H' COLONY, INDIRA NAGAR 1ST STAGE,

BANGALORE-560038

Hobbies & Activities

• Participated in Various Tech Conferences at Thomson Reuters

- Participated in Volunteer Programs for Oxfam India
- Participated in Blood Donation by Rotary International
- Have participated in District and State Level General Knowledge, Tourism and Technical Quizzes
- Have created working projects in Openshift PaaS
- Developing simple products using latest technologies that I feel interested like mongodb, node.js..
- Browsing websites like dzone, stackexchange etc. for information on various technologies

Declaration

I hereby declare that all the details furnished above are true to the best of my knowledge and belief as on 25-Feb-2015.

BABU VIGNESH